Touhidur Rahman

+8801723427078

House No: 01, Shyamoli Ring Road, Dhaka-1207, Bangladesh abircse06@gmail.com

Computer Engineer with 14 years' experience(professionally 9 years) in designing, developing and implement computer based software. Have excellent technical and communication skill with a goal focused professional mind. I am motivated and enthusiastic by new challenges and tasks and always try to take best possible approach to achieve success in all projects.



Experience

09/2011 to 05/2015

Software Engineer

Noobis, Inc, Buffalo, New York

- Develop and maintain client based and in house web application.
- Learn new tech and try to use those for new or on going projects.

06/2015 to 11/2017

Senior Software Engineer

Noobis Inc, Buffalo, New York

- Implement agile development process for client based and in-house application.
- Manage and lead the backed api development team
- Lead and directly involved into in-house mobile app development.

12/2017 to 11/2019

Tech Team Lead and Manager

Noobis Inc, Buffalo, New York

- Lead the entire tech team.
- Manage the development flow of high featured SaaS apps.
- Bring up new in-house app ideas .

01/2020 to Present

Team Lead and Manager

Developer Squad, New York

- Lead the entire tech team.
- Manage projects and clients

Education

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science and Engineering (Feb

2007 - July 2011)

Institute: Rajshahi University of Engineering and Technology

Profiles

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/touhidur
 GitHub: github.com/touhidurabir
 Twitter: twitter.com/abirtouhidur

Skills

- Languages: C, C++, PHP, Ruby, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Frameworks : Laravel(PHP)
 Symfony(PHP), Rails(Ruby), Vue(JS),
 Bootstrap(CSS), Tailwind(CSS)
- Mobile App: iOS and Android(using Appcelerator Studio)
- Database : MySQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL
- OS: MAC OS(primary), Linux, Windows
- **Design** : Responsive, UX
- Cloud Service : AWS, Digitalocean, GCC
- Fluent English Speaking and Writing

Notable Projects

- fanfundit.com (Laravel, Vue)
- shapla.io (Laravel, Vue, Node, Golang)
- webapp.serlockintegrated.com (Laravel, Vue)
- lawmaker.io (Rails)
- americasnextinvestment.com (WP, Laravel, React)
- trustos.org (Laravel)
- express.buffalocitymission.org (Laravel, TALL stack)
- pickabrick.org (Laravel, React)
- buffalonextcenturygalarsvp.org (Laravel, React)